No going back.
TRON: Ares is a science fiction, adventure, action
film directed by Joachim Rønning.
A highly sophisticated Program called Ares is sent from the digital world into the real
world on a dangerous mission, marking humankind's first encounter with A.I.
Ares, played by Jared Leto.
Eve Kim, played by Greta Lee.
Julian Dillinger, played by Evan Peters.
Elisabeth Dillinger, played by Gillian Anderson.
Athena, played by Jodie Turner-Smith.
Kevin Flynn, played by Jeff Bridges.
Tron: Ares is a 2025 American science fiction action film directed by Joachim Rønning
and written by Jesse Wigutow, from a story by Wigutow and David DiGilio.
It is the third installment in the Tron series
and sequel to Tron: Legacy (2010).
The film stars Jared Leto, Greta Lee, Evan Peters, Jodie Turner-Smith, Hasan Minhaj, Arturo Castro, and
Gillian Anderson, with Jeff Bridges reprising his role as Kevin Flynn from the first two films.
The story is about artificial intelligence originating from the Grid entering
the real world, namely a highly advanced program called Ares.
Development of a sequel to Tron: Legacy began in October
2010 by franchise creator Steven Lisberger.
In March 2017, Walt Disney Pictures shifted plans toward a
soft reboot with Leto playing a new character.
Garth Davis was set as director in August 2020 when Wigutow was
working on the script, but stepped down in January 2023.
Rønning replaced him a month later.
Production was expected to begin in August 2023 but was delayed by the
2023 Writers Guild of America and SAG-AFTRA strikes.
Filming ultimately began in January 2024 in Vancouver and finished in May.
By August, industrial rock band Nine Inch Nails had
been announced to be composing the score.
The band's members, Trent Reznor and Atticus Ross, served as executive
producers on the film, alongside Legacy director Joseph Kosinski.
Tron: Ares premiered in Los Angeles on October 6, 2025, and
went into general release on October 10.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and was considered a box office disappointment,
grossing $142 million worldwide on a production budget of $180–220 million.
The film explores themes of artificial intelligence (a.i.), computer
program, simulation, computer simulation, sequel.
The tone is thought_provoking.